"Be the change that you want to see in the world."

Summary

Lead cloud engineer at financial startup Dispute.com. Provided technical leadership and onboarded a team of 3 engineers, building a strong culture of documentation and testing. 8+ years of varied experience in software engineering specializing in backend development, software architecture, and real time applications. Strong communication skills, with a proven track record of leading teams to clarity on future and current products.

I love to learn new languages as well as deep learning every detail of more frequently used tools. Currently learning Rust, Bevy, and Vim. Specialist in C#, dotnet core, Unity, and Terraform. Excited by working with highly performant and reliable software with passionate teammates.

Work Experience

Dispute.com Milwaukee, Wisconsin (Remote)

SENIOR SOFTWARE ENGINEER

Feb. 2023 - Present

- Build foundational engineering practices to support a small team.
- · Created CICD pipelines in GitHub Actions which deployed applications via Terraform and released internal shared Nuget and NPM packages.

Flite Golf & Entertainment Milwaukee, Wisconsin (Remote)

UNITY IMPLEMENTATION SPECIALIST

Seb. 2022 - Feb. 2023

- Provided company-wide guidance on C# and Unity best practices as the resident Unity expert.
- Reduced build times by splitting project code into assembly definitons.
- Introduced unit tests to an untested codebase.
- Implemented extensible logging solution supporting both cloud-based analytics and local file logging.
- Introduced Azure Application Insights to capture logs and debug all deployments across all facilities.
- · Managed on-site deployment of 36 Unity-based golf simulators, and Flite's client relationship with the independent facility.
- Built foundation for disciplined QA practice by designing standarized test cases.
- · Led towards a culture of documentation and collaboration by creating a knowledge base and onboarding guide.

Centare (Milwaukee Tool) Milwaukee, Wisconsin

AWS CLOUD ENGINEER

Jan. 2021 - Jun. 2021

- Used CQRS and Event Sourcing to build an ETL pipeline from Sql Server into Elasticsearch
- Learned AWS Lambda and the Kinesis Consumer Library in Python to build a serverless data pipeline
- Skills: Python Terraform Docker C# AWS Lambda Dynamodb Kinesis

Centare (Symplr Cactus) Milwaukee, Wisconsin

FULL STACK ANGULAR DEVELOPER

Sep. 2019 - Dec. 2020

- Modernized existing web applications into Angular Single Page Applications.
- Onboarded two offshore teams to work inside the new project ecosystem.
- Skills: Angular Typescript RxJS Cypress C# Web API Agile

Centare (API Healthcare)

Milwaukee, Wisconsin Aug. 2017 - Seb. 2019

- Converted legacy C# on-premise modules to run on the Azure cloud.
- · Managed automated build and deployment in Jenkins.
- Worked on Time and Attendance software used by hospitals across US and Canada.
- Documented and led design decisions for Angular appliations.
- Worked in an organization of 6+ other teams.

CLOUD ENGINEER, ANGULAR APPLICATION DEVELOPER

· Onboarded new team members to support Angular applications by creating a knowledge base and one-on-one mentoring

Brady Corporation Seoul, S.Korea

Jun. 2015 - Dec. 2016 IT DEVELOPMENT INTERN

Honors & Awards

INTERNATIONAL AWARDS

DAN MILLER · RÉSUMÉ SEPTEMBER 3, 2024

2021	2nd Place , AWS ASEAN AI/ML GameDay	Online
2020	Finalist, DEFCON 28th CTF Hacking Competition World Final	Las Vegas, U.S.A
2018	Finalist, DEFCON 26th CTF Hacking Competition World Final	Las Vegas, U.S.A
2017	Finalist, DEFCON 25th CTF Hacking Competition World Final	Las Vegas, U.S.A
2014	Finalist, DEFCON 22nd CTF Hacking Competition World Final	Las Vegas, U.S.A
2013	Finalist, DEFCON 21st CTF Hacking Competition World Final	Las Vegas, U.S.A
2011	Finalist, DEFCON 19th CTF Hacking Competition World Final	Las Vegas, U.S.A
Domes	FIC AWARDS	
2021	2nd Place, AWS Korea GameDay	Seoul, S.Korea
2015	3rd Place , WITHCON Hacking Competition Final	Seoul, S.Korea
2017	Silver Prize, KISA HDCON Hacking Competition Final	Seoul, S.Korea
2013	Silver Prize, KISA HDCON Hacking Competition Final	Seoul, S.Korea
Сомми	NITY	
2022 -	AWS Community Builder (Container), Amazon Web Services (AWS)	
2022 -	HashiCorp Ambassador, HashiCorp	
2018 -	Organizer of HashiCorp Korea User Group, HashiCorp	
Certi	ficates	
2023	AWS Certified Advanced Networking - Specialty, Amazon Web Services (AWS)	
2022	AWS Certified Security - Specialty, Amazon Web Services (AWS)	
2022	AWS Certified Solutions Architect – Professional, Amazon Web Services (AWS)	
2021	AWS Certified SysOps Administrator – Associate, Amazon Web Services (AWS)	
2020	Certified Kubernetes Application Developer (CKAD), The Linux Foundation	
2023	HashiCorp Certified: Consul Associate (002), HashiCorp	
2023	HashiCorp Certified: Terraform Associate (003), HashiCorp	

Education

MSOE Milwaukee, Wi

B.S. IN SOFTWARE ENGINEERING

Sept. 2012 - May 2017

• Some stuff happened.